Gor Mkhitaryan

Java Developer https://mypy125.github.io/Portfolio/

I am a Java developer with four years of specialized education in developing and optimizing client-server applications, with a strong background in computer science.

One of my key projects was the development of a food ordering web application. On the backend, I used Java with the Spring framework, implemented authentication using JWT, integrated the payment system with Idram easypay, and ensured data security. On the frontend, I worked with JavaScript, utilizing React, Redux for state management, and Axios for API communication. The project involved the full development cycle, including architecture design, feature implementation, testing, and optimization. Open to new challenges, I am ready to take on tasks that help me grow my skills and contribute significantly to project success.

Experience

SkillBox java developer 2024 - present

At SkillBox, my approach is based on sharing experience and support at every stage of learning. Now I share my experience and knowledge by helping students create modern and effective web applications.

GeekBrains java developer 2021 - present

Mentored students in Java and backend development.

Provided consultations, code reviews,
(Spring Boot, JPA, REST APIs, DB).

Helped students gain hands-on experience in building client-server applications.

Demonstrated modern development tools: Maven/Gradle, Git, Docker.

Projects

E-commerce multi vendor 2024 - present

https://ecommerce-multivendor-frontend.onrender.com

Developed an e-commerce platform with roles: buyers, sellers, admins. Configured payments (Stripe/PayPal) and email notifications. Accelerated API by 30% using Redis and DB optimization. Provided security: encryption, protection from attacks. Automated reports for sellers. Teamwork: Managed a team of 3 developers. Implemented CI/CD (GitHub Actions), accelerating deployment by 40%.

Restaurant September 2023 - present

https://restaurant-frontend-9jwn.onrender.com/

Conducted market research and trend analysis to identify in-demand products. Initiated and developed a food ordering application to help users conveniently order meals from home.

Phone: +374 44 08 21 24

Email: gor1990.mkhitatryan@gmail.com

LInkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/gor-mk

GitHub: https://github.com/mypy125

Skills

languages Java, JavaScript, TypeScript SQL

Frameworks Spring Boot, Cloud, Webflux, Spring Security, jwt, oauth2, RabbitMQ, JDBC, JPA, Flyway, Liquibase, Hibernate, Netflix, Eureka, Zuul, Hystrix, Load Balancer, Payment integration stripe, paypal etc.

Network and Web technology

TCP/IP, UDP,HTTP, HTTPS,SSL/TLS, JSON, RESTful API, HTML, CSS, Postman, node.js, react- redux, Axios, nestjs

Database MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis,

Tools and technologies CI/CD, Git, AWS ec2,RDS, Docker, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven, Apache, Tomcat, Nginx

Architectural Code and Pattern SOLID, OOP, AOP, DDD, DAO, MVC, MVP, MVVM,Gateway, Proxy and other

Methodologies Agile, Scrum

Testing Testing TDD, JUnit, Mockito,

Restaurant steak technology

Spring Web, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate PostgreSQL, Spring Security, JWT Library Payment system (Stripe, Idram, easypay)

JavaScript (ES6+), Node.js, React, React-Redux Axios, CSS (MUI), Yup, Cloudinary

Shop January 2021

Created an inventory and product management system to optimize inventory and sales processes in retail. Developed features for creating new products, adding them to the warehouse, selling items, and checking product expiration dates. This project demonstrated my skills in designing business logic and managing data for inventory systems.

Education

GeekBrains development, September 2020- January 2024, Udemy Spring Professional Certification 2024

Languages

English B2, Russian B2